# **MECHATRONICS ENGINEER - SPECIALIZED IN POWER ELECTRONICS**



As a mechatronics engineer with a core focus on power electronics, I can contribute to all phases of your product development life cycle from concept development to its final deployment as well as features upgrade. My education enables me to understand various dynamic systems such as wind turbines, electric drives, and power converters and implement various control algorithms in simulation while transferring the algorithms to embedded software and integrating it with the appropriate firmware. I have software development, mechatronics product development, control system design, power electronics, and hardware-in-the-loop skills. I thrive in a diverse teamwork environment, and I can learn new concepts very fast.

### **EDUCATION/TRAINING**

• OCT 2022 - PRESENT Codecaademy

MAY 2022 - PRESENT Typhoon HIL Academy (HIL Specialist 2.0 Certified)

SEP 2019 - DEC 2021 MSc Mechatronics - Power Electronics, University of Southern Denmark

JAN 2018 - AUG 2019 MSc Control and Instrumentation Engineering, University of Ibadan, Nigeria (Incomplete)

SEP 2011 - JUNE 2016 B.Eng. Electrical-Electronic Engineering, Covenant University, Nigeria

#### **PROJECTS**

DEC 2022 - DEC 2022 Explorative Data Processing/Analysis of Stack Overflow Survey Trend.

DEC 2022 - DEC 2022 Tuning of Field Oriented Control for a Synchronous Permanent Magnet Machine

• MAY 2022 - JUN 2022 Real-Time Simulation of a Simple Electric Drive System and Microgrid on Typhoon HIL CCS.

JAN 2021 - DEC 2021 BLDC Machine Controller for a Low Power Electric Vehicle (Thesis at GCM A/S).

SEP 2020 - DEC 2020 The Adaptive non-linear control of a multi-tank system.

JAN 2020 - MAY 2020 Conformal 3D printing using a robotic arm.

JAN 2020 - MAY 2020 Parameter Estimation of Physical processes and systems.

SEP 2019 - JAN 2020 Implementation of Particle swarm optimization (PSO) algorithm.

JAN 2016 - MAY 2016 Implementation of an intelligent battery powered lighting system.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

• JUL 2020 - AUG 2022 Cleaning Service, Torve Hallen, Sønderborg.

JAN 2017 - AUG 2019 Freelance Technical Content Writer for Tacuna Systems, Upwork, USA.

LANGUAGES	IT SKILLS	
English ( >20 yrs)  Danish ( >2 yrs)	MATLAB/Simulink (8yrs) Control Systems Design (4yrs) Embedded C (8yrs) Python/C/C++ (3yrs)	
	Typhoon HIL CCS ( < 1yr) Software Test(Pytest/Mocha/UnitTest) ( < 1yr)	
	Data analysis (<1yr) Sensors/actuators(1yr)	

# **ABOUT ME**

I train in martial arts as a fun way to stay fit. I enjoy it because it is a creative sport that allows for a lot of structural collaboration between sparring partners with different skills and from different nations/cultures. And it has taught me that it is okay not to be an expert at everything, but if one is willing to work hard, it is possible to win over challenges. Besides this, I like to relax by watching movies with genres including Science fiction, documentaries, comedy, and romance.